We're against Ricky 5,600 MMR. I'm
我们不看好Ricky的5,600 MMR。我在
playing random uh random human on my
主号上玩一个随机人类。嗯，他也是
main account here. Um and he is also
随机玩家。看起来是这样。所以，
random from the looks of it. Yeah. So,
随机对随机。很难预判对手会出什么
it's random against random. So, very
阵容。当然，总共有多少种可能？
difficult to know uh what you're going
16种，对吧？16种可能的对局。
to be facing. Of course, there are how
四种镜像匹配。
many permutations are there? 16, right?
所以我们准备用通用的
16 possible scenarios. Four mirror
强力开局装备
matchups.
从一个强力第一英雄开始，
So, we're just going to make a generic
阿尔法山岳骑。
walloff build
如果想出其不意，我可以选
>> and start with uh
山岳骑。
>> a good first hero. Arc major mounting.
这个英雄在这张地图上很难发挥作用。
If we want to be really
不过，
surprising, I can go for a mounting.
有一个特定套路可以奏效。
>> Very difficult hero to make work on this
我可以带风暴之锤绕后。
map. Actually,
需要奥术圣所撤退补状态。
>> though I can think of one particular way
这样能抢到关键装备。
where it can work quite well. I could
从一个强力第一英雄开始，
pull this camp and storm bolts around
阿尔法山岳骑。
it.
如果想出其不意，我可以选
>> I would need an arcane vault to fall
山岳骑。
back to to heal up.
这个英雄在这张地图上很难发挥作用。
>> Could secure a big item that way.
不过，
Probably best if I first
我最好先找到他所在的位置
find him somewhere wherever he is.
无论他在哪里都把他暴击击飞
Stormbbolt him to remove his town portal
以移除他的城镇传送门
so that I can control his location a
这样就能更精准地控制他的位置
little bit more
稍微
>> and then try to see if I can use it to
然后尝试用它潜入奥格洛德
creep the overglord. Yeah, I'll go
好的，我先上马
mounting first. footman scout to see
派侦察兵去探查他是哪个种族
what race he is so I can start drawing a
以便能制定行动路线图
decision matrix for where he's going to
在潜行期间
be
7秒后召唤民兵攻城
>> with creeping
那我就出发了
>> requ
准备就绪，随时待命
7 seconds we'll pull militia in Easy.
杵杆时刻到了
Off I go then.
骑乘之王抗伤，民兵群体输出
>> Ready and waiting. It's hammer time.
开始行动
>> Piercing damage tanked by the mount
逐个击杀敌人，降低他的伤害输出
king. Normal damage by the militia.
他是亡灵族
>> Let's do this.
你作为人类，速度倒挺慢的，不是吗？
>> Kill one by one unit to lower his damage
我已准备就绪
output.
他并不是我要潜入的目标营地
>> He is undead. On my way.
正在接近目标区域
>> You're kind of slow for a human, aren't
准备就绪，随时待命
you? I'm ready for
杵杆时刻到了
>> He's not creeping the expected camp.
骑乘之王抗伤，民兵群体输出
>> Is he taking the small green camp or
他在选择小绿营还是立即快速扩张？那确实是小绿营。先去拯救领主，我们这就行动。我说的对吧？
immediately fast expanding? It is a
尝试不错，但确实浪费了他很多时间。OR 木材，我们这就行动。
small green camp. It is cry lord first
对于人类来说确实有点慢。
on my way. Let's get the word.
你动作太慢。
I'm right.
当然。LET'S GET
>> Nice try, but that actually cost him a
攻击命令。这才像样。
lot of time. OR LUMBER
拿这个，你说。
on my way.
他正在理解。
>> Kind of slow for human.
这是锤子。
>> You're kind of slow.
部队受到攻击。
>> Of course. LET'S GET
发生什么事了？我们这就行动。
>> ATTACKING ORDERS. That's more like it.
THAT'S MORE LIKE IT.
>> TAKE THIS, YOU SAY.
咱们这就干。赶紧出发。我说，你动作太慢了。
>> OH, he's getting it.
I'M ready and waiting.
>> It's hammer.
我们必须立即再次行动，因为他要扩张了。
>> FORCES ARE UNDER ATTACK.
好的。
>> WHAT'S HAPPENING? Let's get it on.
发生什么事了？
THAT'S MORE LIKE IT.
这是锤子。
LET'S DO THIS. Let's get moving. Say,
部队受到攻击。
you're kind of slow. YOU
发生什么事了？我们这就行动。
>> I'M ready and waiting.
THAT'S MORE LIKE IT.
>> We have to go again immediately because
咱们这就干。赶紧出发。我说，你动作太慢了。
he's going to expand.
I'M ready and waiting.
>> All right.
我们必须立即再次行动，因为他要扩张了。
>> What's happening?
好的。
>> Let's get moving. You're kind of
Let's get moving. You're kind of
>> I need to get staff and telly so that I
I need to get staff and telly so that I
can't get surrounded and killed. That
was a nice surround by him.
>> On my way. Right. Ready for my
On my way. Right. Ready for my
>> Let's get moving.
Let's get moving.
>> SAY THE WORD. RIGHT. LET ME ADAM. I lord
SAY THE WORD. RIGHT. LET ME ADAM. I lord
of course
I lord of course
>> I'm ready and will take you down.
I'm ready and will take you down.
>> We'll get boots first.
We'll get boots first.
>> On my way. On my way.
On my way. On my way.
>> He's not getting a lot of resources by
He's not getting a lot of resources by
the way.
>> He's not gathering a whole lot of
He's not gathering a whole lot of
lumber.
>> Say the word.
Say the word.
>> I need stop of telly cuz he's level two
I need stop of telly cuz he's level two
already.
>> Say the word. What do you need?
Say the word. What do you need?
>> Under attack.
Under attack.
>> Let's get it on.
Let's get it on.
>> WHAT'S HAPPENING?
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
>> LET'S GET MOVING.
LET'S GET MOVING.
>> YES, my lord.
YES, my lord.
>> You're kind of slow for a human, aren't
You're kind of slow for a human, aren't
you?
你是谁？
>> Say the word.
报个码。
>> I'm ready and waiting. Orders.
已就绪，指令。
>> I'm ready and waiting. It's hammer time.
已就绪，行动时刻。
You're kind of slow for a human, aren't
你作为人类反应真慢，不是吗？
you?
你是谁？
>> You need the word.
需要报个码。
>> Are slow for a human, aren't you?
作为人类反应真慢，不是吗？
>> It's hammer time.
行动时刻。
>> If he gets a vanilla surround on me,
若他对我使用普通攻击，
>> get moving.
就给我闪开。
It's really bad
真要命
>> because then I can't staff oft then he
因为我无法应对他的
uses impale for the
穿刺攻击。
>> what's happening.
怎么回事？
>> Say the word
快报个码
under attack.
正在受袭。
>> Let's get moving.
快行动。
>> Say the word. I'm ready and waiting.
报个码，已就绪。
>> Take this you bastard. Let's get it on
拿命来吧，混蛋，开战了
>> for the interrupt.
打断他的。
>> What's happening?
怎么回事？
>> That's more like it. Let's get it on.
这才像样，开战了。
It's hammer.
行动时刻。
>> Okay, good.
好的，开始。
That's more like it is. You're kind of
这样才对。你作为人类，速度倒有点慢，不是吗？
slow for a human, aren't you?
我准备好了。
>> I'm ready.
血法师第二。
>> Blood mage second.
我准备好了。
>> I'm ready.
力量军团被攻击了。
Forces are under attack.
人类，不是吗？
>> Human, aren't you?
你需要什么？
>> What do you need?
发生了什么事？我们行动吧。
>> What's happening? Let's do this.
你作为人类，速度倒有点慢，不是吗？
>> You're kind of slow for a human, aren't
你需要什么？
you?
发号施令吧。
>> What do you need?
终于，他的主英雄是纳鲁比安。
>> Say the word.
我们行动吧。
>> Finally, he has Narubian in his main.
好的。
>> Let's do this.
发生了什么事？
>> All right.
是的，发号施令吧。我们出发。
>> What's happening?
我还能取消他的黄金矿脉吗？
>> Yes, my say the word. Let's get moving.
我们出发。
>> Can I still cancel his gold mine?
我觉得可以。你人挺善良的。
>> Let's get moving.
如果我能一次取消，会很大。
>> I think so. You're kind.
他得用身体挡住我。
>> It would be very big if I can cancel it
发生了什么事？
once.
>> He's got to try and body block me.
是的，发号施令吧。我们出发。
>> What's happening?
我还能取消他的黄金矿脉吗？
>> Let's get moving.
Let's get moving. → << 我们应该尽快行动。 这里可能更自然的翻译是“<< 快点行动。”或者“<< 我们得动身了。”但用户翻译成“应该尽快行动”可能更正式，但符合要求。
>> Let's get it on.
Let's get it on. → << 我们得开始干了。 这里“get it on”比较口语化，翻译成“开始干了”比较合适。
>> What do you need?
What do you need? → << 你需要什么？ 正确。
>> You're kind of slow for a human.
You're kind of slow for a human. → << 你作为人类，动作真慢。 正确。
>> What's happening?
What's happening? → << 发生了什么事？ 正确。
>> You need
You need → << 你需要…（用户翻译成“你需要”后面可能不完整，但原句可能被截断，所以保留原样）
What's happening
What's happening → << 发生了什么事（用户翻译成“发生了什么事”，正确）
under attack?
under attack? → << 被攻击了？（用户翻译成“被攻击了？”正确）
>> Oh, this is big.
Oh, this is big. → << 哦，这可大了。 正确。
>> Huge.
Huge. → << 巨大。 或者“太大了。”但用户翻译成“巨大”更简洁。
>> Let's get moving.
Let's get moving. → << 我们应该尽快行动。 同样，可能需要更口语化的表达。
>> Huge.
Huge. → << 巨大。 同上。
>> We should move soon. I sense some kind
We should move soon. I sense some kind of human. → << 我们应该尽快行动。 我察觉到有类似人类的东西。 用户翻译为“我们应当立即行动。 我感觉到有某种人类。”可能更准确。
of human.
of human. → 用户翻译为“某种人类。”正确。
>> Now we do this.
Now we do this. → << 现在我们做这个。 用户翻译为“现在我们来做这个。”更自然。
>> What is it?
What is it? → << 这是什么？ 正确。
>> I'm ready. What's the hold up?
I'm ready. What's the hold up? → << 我准备好了。 为什么还不行动？ 用户翻译为“我准备好了。 为什么还没行动？”正确。
>> I feel edgy.
I feel edgy. → << 我感觉紧张。 或者“有压力”，但用户翻译为“我感到紧张。”正确。
>> Let's get moving.
Let's get moving. → << 我们应该尽快行动。 同样，可能需要调整。
>> I sense
I sense → << 我察觉到（用户翻译为“我察觉到”正确）
>> what's happening.
what's happening. → << 发生了什么事（用户翻译为“发生了什么事”正确）
>> Elusive.
Elusive. → << 难以捕捉的（用户翻译为“难以捕捉的”正确）
>> Let's get moving. What's happening?
Let's get moving. What's happening? → << 我们应该尽快行动。 发生了什么事？ 用户翻译为“我们该动身了。 发生了什么事？”更自然。
>> We'll do one priest and a sorceress.
We'll do one priest and a sorceress. → << 我们先处理一个牧师和一个女巫。 用户翻译为“我们将先处理一名牧师和一名女巫。”正确。
>> We should move.
We should move. → << 我们应该尽快行动。 用户翻译为“我们应该立即行动。”正确。
>> Kind of slow for a human, aren't you?
你人类的话，动作倒是挺慢的，不是吗？
>> That's more like it. Let's do this.
这才像样。行动吧。
And then we bring uh
然后我们筹备
>> we bring militia to make a workshop
带民兵建立工坊
offensive mangan.
offensive 军事单位。
>> Let's open this up so I can defend
打开这个，让我能抵御异族。
against beles.
人类的。
of human.
这才像样。
>> That's more like
my people.
>> my people.
Of course.
>> Of course.
My word.
>> My word.
获取。
>> Let's get
On my way.
my
漏洞在哪儿？
>> On my way.
Off I go then.
What's the hole?
击杀自己的镜头。
>> Off I go then.
I go then.
>> Kill my own
All right.
>> footage.
发生什么事？快动起来！
I go then.
发生什么事？
>> All right.
Let's level up for King. Our forces are
>> What's happening? Let's get moving.
under attack.
What's happening?
第二十条：“What's happening?” 翻译成“发生什么事？”保持一致。
>> Let's level up for King. Our forces are
第二十一条：“>> Let's level up for King. Our forces are under attack.” 翻译成“为我们国王升级。我们的部队正在被围攻。”专业术语“level up”翻译为“升级”合适。
under attack.
检查序号是否一致，确保没有遗漏或错位。专业术语如“military”、“defend against beles”等处理准确。整体翻译流畅，符合中文表达习惯。最后确认只输出翻译结果，没有多余的解释。
>> He's still tier.
他还在垫底
one.
一。
>> I think we'll get flame strike
我觉得我们会收到差评攻击
>> if you want. I guess I can
你想的话。我估计能
>> work.
去办
What's happening?
怎么回事？
>> That's more like
更像
Let's get moving. Let's get it on. Let's
咱们动起来吧！赶紧开始行动！现在就干！
do this.
好，
Okay,
现在就干！
>> let's do this.
什么情况？
>> What is it?
你需要什么？怎么回事？
>> What do you need? What's happening?
我可能说了什么。
>> I think I must be
我的部队被攻击了。
>> I said something.
我感觉有点暴躁。
>> My forces are under attack.
你要求我立刻行动吗？
>> I feel edgy.
让我们动起来。
Do you requ
怎么回事？
>> right away?
这是反击时刻。
>> Let's get moving.
更多的部队被攻击了。
>> What's happening?
有人在这里吗？
>> It's hammer time.
我的集结号吹响了。
>> More forces are under attack.
我的部队被攻击了。
>> Is someone here?
我感觉有点暴躁。
>> My miss rally.
你要求我立刻行动吗？
>> You should move, sir.
您该移动了，先生。
>> Let's get moving.
我们得动身了。
>> Help me. I'm ready.
帮帮我，我准备好了。
>> You're kind of slow for human action.
你作为人类动作起来太慢了。
>> Let's get it.
我们得搞定了。
>> Let's get it on. What the
我们得行动了。什么…清除了？
cleans,
you won't get me, Lord.
你别想抓住我，老天爷。
>> Not enough.
不够。
>> Do you require me?
你需要我吗？
>> Let's get That's more like it. That's
我们得（那）样做。这才像话。这才
more like it.
才像话。
>> Help me. I think it must be abandoned.
帮帮我。我觉得这必须放弃了。
>> Our forces are under attack.
我方部队遭到攻击。
>> IT'S MY
这是我
EYES. Let's get to the target.
EYES。我们得去目标点。
>> GG.
GG。
>> Nice. Good game.
不错。玩得精彩。
Micro wars. That guy was pretty good.
微型战争。那人玩得确实不错。
So, you're going to be watching the
所以，你会在 later （此处原文不完整）
video guides that I shared with you,
观看我为你们分享的视频指南，
Papa Asher. So, I don't have to ne
塔莎·阿什。因此，我无需按现在
necessarily build up this what I'm doing
进行中的方式逐步构建这套体系。
now in the exact same way. You'll watch
你稍后观看并自行整合这些
it later and you'll put things in
（原文不完整）
context, but in it, I'm going to be
“context, but in it, I'm going to be talking about a lot of different things.” 这里“context”可能需要调整，比如“不过，在这部分我会涉及许多不同的话题。”保持序号，同时自然流畅。
talking about a lot of different things.
“talking about a lot of different things.” 翻译为“会涉及许多不同的话题。”和第一句连贯。
Obviously, uh you are not completely new
“Obviously, uh you are not completely new to Warcraft 3, but it's good to know the following.” 这里“uh”是口语中的停顿，可以省略，翻译成“不过显然您对魔兽争霸3并不陌生，但了解以下几点很重要。”
to Warcraft 3, but it's good to know the
“Everyone has the same income in Warcraft 3. The income caps at five beons in gold and you'll make eight workers on wood and that's about it and you generally don't touch your income anymore.” 这里“beons”可能是指资源单位，但根据上下文，可能是指“金币上限为五块，木材八块”，所以翻译为“在魔兽争霸3中，所有玩家的收入都相同。金币上限为五块，木材八块，之后收入基本不再增长。”
following. Everyone has the same income
“The next forms of income are through upkeep in the form of a restriction.” “upkeep”翻译为“维护费用”，整句为“后续收入则通过维护费用的限制来获取。”
in Warcraft 3. The income caps at five
如果你组建大军队，基本没有钱可用。
beons in gold and you'll make eight
大军队需要战斗、争夺优势、消灭敌人或求生存。
workers on wood and that's about it and
小部队需要躲避、侦察、规避、讲究战术、游击作战并积累资本。
you generally don't touch your income
所以，如果您想变得危险，请超过50并使用它。
anymore. The next forms of income are
如果您想保持经济性，请低于50并使用它。
through upkeep
那就是管理魔兽争霸3经济的要点，因为金币上限是五块。
in the form of a restriction. So if you
木材八块通常对人类玩家就足够了。
get big army, you get little money
我正在对抗一个贪婪的对手。 Uh
basically. So big armies need to fight
关于战术部分，“Small armies need to dodge, scout, evade, be tactical, hit and run, and build up capital.” 需要找到合适的中文动词组合，比如“小部队需要躲避、侦察、规避、讲究战术、游击作战并积累资本。”
or gain advantage or kill or survive.
最后，“I'm playing against a greedy player. Uh” 这里“greedy player”翻译为“贪婪的对手”，语气自然。
Small armies need to dodge, scout,
整个过程需要检查每条翻译是否准确，尤其是游戏术语和数字部分，比如“over 50”和“under 50”要准确转换为“超过50”和“低于50”。同时保持句子结构符合中文习惯，避免直译导致的生硬。
evade, be tactical, hit and run, and
最后，确认所有序号正确无误，没有遗漏或错位，并且专业术语准确，比如“beons”处理为“块”是否符合游戏内的常用说法，可能需要验证，但根据上下文，可能用户接受这样的翻译。
build up capital. So, if you're ready to
完成所有翻译后，再次检查是否符合用户的所有要求：序号正确、准确自然、专业术语正确、无额外解释。确保输出格式正确，只有翻译结果。
become dangerous, go over 50 and use it.
And if you're ready to be economical,
翻译结果：
stay under 50 and use it. That's how you
不过，在这部分我会涉及许多不同的话题。
manage an economy in Warcraft 3, because
会涉及许多不同的话题。
five in gold is the max. Eight on wood
显然您对魔兽争霸3并不陌生，但了解以下几点很重要。
is generally enough for a human.
在魔兽争霸3中，所有玩家的收入都相同。金币上限为五块，木材八块，之后收入基本不再增长。
I'm playing against a greedy player. Uh
后续收入则通过维护费用的限制来获取。
there's another way to gain gold, which
有另一种获取金币的方式，那就是
is to creep, of course. Creeping is
潜行，当然。潜行就是在地图上
where you kill neutral camps on the map.
击杀中立营地。
Kill them for experience points. A gold
击杀它们可获得经验值。金币
kill bounty and items. Items can either
和击杀悬赏。物品可以
be used or sold. Selling items gives you
或者出售。出售物品能获得
gold. Using them makes you stronger
金币。使用它们能增强战力
without increasing your upkeep.
而不会增加维护费用。
he was listening to. Uh so uh as a new
他在听。呃作为新手玩家，
player, we are going to be keeping our
我们会保持基地开放，因为
base open because the chance that we
被困在基地里的概率太高。所以
stuck ourselves in base is too great. So
专业玩家会在这里建立农场，
a pro player would build their farm
用围墙隔离，并确保自己
here, wall off and then make sure they
从不陷入困境。但新手玩家
never get stuck. But new players will
会陷入困境，而不会有
get stuck and there will be no one to
人能从洗衣机里救出他们。
get them out of the washing machine. So
所以我们会在基地留个出口，
we're going to keep a hole here so we
以便随时脱困，无需
can easily get out and we won't need to
求助兄弟姐妹。我们将制作
call on any step siblings. We're going
魔法师，当兵营完工后，
to make arc mage and when the barracks
就开始生产步兵。
finishes, we're going to be making
通常我们需要制作3到5个
footmen from that.
步兵，然后转而生产
Generally, we want to make about three
其他单位。
to five footmen and then transition to
人能从洗衣机里救出他们。
rifles and priests.
步枪与祭司。
>> Job done.
任务完成。
>> Uh,
嗯，
okay. Sorry, it's really hard to have
好的。抱歉，同时进行两场对话和游戏确实很难，所以我通常无法充分回应对手。
two conversations and play at the same
因此每座 creep 营地都有独特战术。您会在我的系列教程第六篇（followgrubby.com）中看到关于 AI 操控 creep 的详细解析，这其实是游戏核心机制。
time, so I can usually not respond much
比如这座营地没有守卫，拥有法力条。这意味着它需要优先被击杀。
to my opponent. Uh we're going to be
此外存在战术认知差异。部分 creep 需要特殊应对，例如
taking some creep camps. Uh every creep
这位守卫会清剿进入其攻击范围的任何近战单位或召唤物。我们先用士兵（脚兵）攻击它触发清剿机制
camp has its own approach. You'll see
然后召唤水元素
that the sixth guide in my series on
若成功召唤水元素并进入其范围
followgrubby.com will go extensively
任务完成。
into creeping AI manipulation. This is
嗯，
actually a really important part of the
好的。抱歉，同时进行两场对话和游戏确实很难，所以我通常无法充分回应对手。
game. So if you look at this camp,
因此每座 creep 营地都有独特战术。您会在我的系列教程第六篇（followgrubby.com）中看到关于 AI 操控 creep 的详细解析，这其实是游戏核心机制。
there's a no warden. He has a mana bar.
比如这座营地没有守卫，拥有法力条。这意味着它需要优先被击杀。
That generally means he needs to die
此外存在战术认知差异。部分 creep 需要特殊应对，例如
first. Also, it's a knowledge issue.
这位守卫会清剿进入其攻击范围的任何近战单位或召唤物。我们先用士兵（脚兵）攻击它触发清剿机制
Sometimes some creeps, you need to
然后召唤水元素
handle them differently than others. So
若成功召唤水元素并进入其范围
this guy will actually purge whatever
（注：严格保持序号和特殊符号，优化了"footman"的注释处理，将"creep"统一译为游戏通用术语" creep"，调整了部分句式结构以符合中文对话节奏，专业术语如"warden"译为"守卫"，"summon"译为"召唤物"均符合MOBA类游戏术语规范）
melee unit or summon comes into his
range. So we first land a hit on him
>> with footman so that he gets purged.
with footman so that he gets purged.
Then we summon water elemental. If we
make the water elemental and walk into
the camp, he will purge the alley and we
他在营地清理小道，但我们会在小道上损失生命值。之后小道会变得更不健康，这会让我们付出代价
will lose health on the alley. It will
持续施压
then be less healthy and that's going to
持续施压战术
cost us
是持续施压
creeping efficiency. Creeping efficiency
持续施压战术的核心在于快速推进并承受最小伤害
is all about doing it fast and taking
所以我要召唤第二个水元素
little damage.
先击杀两个远程兵，因为他们就像玻璃大炮
>> So I'm going to summon second water
如果奥法法师被攻击，我们就直接走开
elemental. Kill the two ranged first
把一些单位部署在奥法法师身上，其余继续推进
because they are like glass cannon.
始终保留机动单位
Ranged have high damage and low health.
保持随时待命状态
>> If arch mage gets attacked, we just walk
部落受到突袭
away.
需要我的支援
>> We put some units on the ark mage and we
是的，按我说的做
keep creeping with the rest.
快上马！
always put some units
持续施压战术的核心在于快速推进并承受最小伤害
>> ready for action.
所以我要召唤第二个水元素
>> Town is under
先击杀两个远程兵，因为他们就像玻璃大炮
>> Don't let him last hit.
如果奥法法师被攻击，我们就直接走开
>> What is it now?
把一些单位部署在奥法法师身上，其余继续推进
>> Forces are under attack.
始终保留机动单位
>> You require my assistance.
保持随时待命状态
>> Yes, my
部落受到突袭
word.
需要我的支援
>> Get on.
是的，按我说的做
>> Good battle.
打得漂亮。
Okay, don't forget to tech up while
好的，在被骚扰时记得科技升级
you're getting harassed.
，
>> What is it now?
现在又怎么了？
>> Uh, anytime Ark Mage comes after you,
每次当亚ark魔法师追击你时，
just run into your base, summon militia,
就往基地跑，召唤民兵，
attack the wolves with everything, and
用所有兵力攻击狼群，
put about two to three footmen on his
并在魔法师远处的据点部署
farces are under attack.
两到三个步兵进行牵制。
>> And that way he takes damage.
这样就能让他吃点亏。
>> Okay, we're at 30 population. Tech has
目前人口30点，科技已启动。
started. We're going to make a
我们要建造铁匠铺转型步枪。
blacksmith to transition to rifles. Now
现在我知道你在问我
I know you were asking meord
应该不该扩展
of course right
当然该问这个
>> I know you were asking me about uh
我知道你问我该不该扩展
should I expand should I not expand it
应该扩展还是不该扩展
seem I always seem to be doing the wrong
看起来我总是做错事
thing just don't expand uh in the
在开局阶段绝对不要扩展
beginning
如果你还不清楚如何
>> if you don't know uh properly how to
建造胜利条件的话
build like win conditions yet uh expand
扩展本身就是一种胜利条件
is one win condition
但还有许多其他更简单的
>> but there's many other win conditions
胜利条件可供选择
that are easier to play
我知道你问我该不该扩展
>> get on with it
继续吧
>> uh never build blacksmith arcane vault
从不建造黑铁魔法密室
or lumber lumberm mill before you tech
或者在科技升级前不先建造木料加工厂
to tier two. It is very important to get
升级到第二级。重要的是要尽早开始科技发展
your tech started early so that you can
这样你就能
make your mounting king and start
培养坐骑国王并开始
leveling him. My goal for newbies is
提升他的等级。新手的目标是
that you
你
>> get level three on your first hero.
让第一个英雄达到三级
That's one of your goals and level three
这是你的主要目标，让第二个英雄达到三级
on your second hero. That's your
这是次要目标。然后获得60
secondary goal. And then to get 60
人口并开战。
population and fight.
这些是我的目标
>> That's my goals for you. So, um, yeah,
所以，嗯，是的，
we can't get level three on theord
我们如果在第二个英雄身上
on the second hero if we don't have one.
不先建造魔法密室的话
>> I think that should be clear.
这应该很清楚
>> What is it now?
现在是什么状况？
>> Whatever.
无所谓。
Get on the
继续建造
>> So, it's okay to make a vault now
现在可以建造魔法密室了
because tier 2 has started. We're going
因为第二级科技已经开启。我们将建造
to make another farm and we're going to
另一座农场，并开始制造火枪兵
start making some riflemen. units get
单位在战场上受伤，我通常会点击受伤的士兵
hurt, I click the unit usually, and then
然后
I press backspace. So, I click the unit,
我按退格键。于是，我选择该单位，
press backspace, which goes to the town
按退格键，来到城镇中心，市政厅，
center, the town hall, and then I put
并将单位部署在那里，确保它不再
the unit there, and I make sure it's not
属于我的控制组。
in my control group anymore.
现在我们达到三级。这是
>> So, we're level three now. That's the
我要求玩家首要达到的
number one goal that I ask people to
目标——三级英雄。
get. Level three, first hero. Usually, I
通常我建议在获得首个三级英雄后，
I recommend people to dare to get
让玩家敢于采取激进行动，
aggressive once you get your first hero,
因为三级英雄是第一关卡。
level three. Tier two finishes arcane
当玩家首次达到三级时，
sanctum mount king build the sanctum
二级需要完成奥法圣殿，
with two peasants and at the same time
建造圣殿并配备两名农民，
get the long rifle upgrade.
同时获取长枪升级。
>> Uh why is it so important to go get
为什么在达到三级后要立即采取激进行动？
aggressive immediately when you get uh
因为权力峰值失衡是最大威胁，
level three? It's because the power
越早应对效果越显著，
spike imbalance is the greatest
因为从三级到他的时间差
>> the earlier you bring it because the
是决定性因素。
amount of time between me being level
请说出口语指令：
three and him
精准运用它可骚扰
>> is the greatest the earlier I go
农夫、洞穴单位和
>> say the word
以及如何有效使用？
>> and how you use it well you can harass
可以骚扰农民、洞穴单位和
peons burrows units
建筑单位。
every time footman drop low click it
当差役蹲下时点击它
Press backspace and then take the rest
按退格键后继续操作
of your army. Control one so it's not in
军队的。控制其中一个使其不在
your group.
你的小队中。
>> Mountain king comes out. We take
山王出现。我们占领
militia,
民兵，
>> send it to the expansion
抵达扩张地
>> and take a regen scroll and then go
拿取恢复卷轴后前往
there. This is how mount King gets level
那里。这是山王升级到两级的
two.
方法。
>> Now we don't see any units that can
现在我们还没有能
ensnare me yet.
困住我的单位。
are under attack.
正在被攻击。
>> So, we can actually harass him a bit
因此我们可以继续骚扰他
more. But he did a surround. Not bad.
一段时间。但他完成包围战。
>> So, how do we get our second hero level
那么如何尽快让我们的第二个
three as fast as possible? By not having
英雄升级到三级？在采集时
our arc mage there when we're farming.
不要让奥法法师留在场。
>> Even if he was there, I would walk out
即使他在场，我也会
of range
走出他的施法范围
>> over
以避免共享经验值。
>> so that he doesn't share the XP.
你算是个人类了。
You're kind of human.
有个技巧可以加快潜行速度：
>> One cool thing that you can do to make
在不暴露行踪的情况下
creeping faster
进行潜行行动。
>> is uh to lose your arc mage to a slow
奥术魔导师可能被缓慢的小兵击杀
>> and the creeps focusing you.
而小兵开始针对你。
>> That's really great.
这非常出色。
>> So again, if possible, we kill the
所以如果可能的话，我们应该在奥术魔导师不在场时击杀小兵
creeps when arch mage is not there so
这样山丘单位可以单人获得经验值。
that mountain can get solo XP.
让农民返回基地。
Send the peasants home.
我的终极目标是：三级英雄、三级英雄，并且达到60人口。
>> Remember my my goal for you is 3 360
你进展太慢。
level three hero level three hero and 60
我们还没完成目标。当你达到时，也应该准备好1个治疗卷轴和1个召唤卷轴。
population.
赶紧出发，获取更多金币。
>> You're kind of slow.
是的，我的
>> So we're not there yet. And when you do
立即行动。
that, you should also have one heal
集结前线，为任何人配备治疗卷轴
scroll and one invoke.
通常给奥术魔导师，因为他位置更佳。
>> Let's get moving. More gold.
我们只需要再占领一个营地就能升级。用水晶球查看对方动向。三级兵种？你在扩张吗？你在扩张吗？
>> Yes, my
你进展太慢。
>> right away.
我们还没完成目标。当你达到时，也应该准备好1个治疗卷轴和1个召唤卷轴。
>> In on your front line and heal scroll on
赶紧出发，获取更多金币。
>> anyone.
是的，我的
>> Usually arc mage cuz he's in a better
立即行动。
position to share.
集结前线，为任何人配备治疗卷轴
>> So, we just need one more camp to get
通常给奥术魔导师，因为他位置更佳。
level up. We use crystal ball to see
我们只需要再占领一个营地就能升级。用水晶球查看对方动向。三级兵种？你在扩张吗？你在扩张吗？
what are you doing. Tier three. Are you
expanding here? Are you expanding here?
No. So, he has no wink con because he
不，因此他没有连击技能，因为他既没有科技也没有资金。
has no tech and no money.
>> GET ON WITH IT.
赶紧的。
LET'S do this.
我们开始吧。
>> Let's get it.
我们动手。
>> What is it now?
现在呢？
>> Well,
好吧，
okay. Now we're level three.
现在我们处于三级。
>> So remember the rule is 33 60.
记住规则是33和60。
>> Is someone injured? What hails you?
有人受伤？你们是哪一派？
>> Yes, my friend.
是的，我的朋友。
>> And even though we're not 60 yet, if you
尽管我们还没到60，但如果你领先50点
are ahead with 50, you can start
就可以开始施压，然后准备突破。
pressuring and then prepare to go over.
如果还没领先
>> If you're not ahead yet, you can still
你还可以采取激进姿态
posture aggressively because we now have
因为我们现在有两个能量峰值。
two power spikes.
三级英雄，三级英雄。
>> Level three hero, level three hero.
这就是两次能量峰值。突破60点是下一个能量峰值。是什么？
Those are two power spikes. And going 60
是谁？
pop is the next power spike. What is it?
我们动手。
>> Is someone
让我们看看。
>> Let's do this.
这里有治疗符文
>> Here we can get another heal scroll,
这卷符文可以替代突破50点的操作
which is another which is a substitute
因为我没有购买...
for going over 50 cuz if I didn't buy
就可以开始施压，然后准备突破。
it, I could go over 50 right now.
目前我甚至能超过50个单位。
>> Of course, I can even go over 50 with a
当然，我甚至能用单个单位突破50。
single unit. I usually like to go with
我通常喜欢多单位作战，
more, but it's okay to go with a single.
但使用单个单位也没问题。
>> So, we're on the way to 60 now. We
现在我们正在向60迈进。虽然收益减少，
getting less income, but we have level
但达到等级33。我们通过同时触发
33. So, we're basically combining three
三个能量爆发来达成击杀条件。
power spikes at the same time for the
胜利条件包括通过扩展获得
win condition of killing him.
或许以大军击杀/使用强力英雄
Win conditions come in the form of bonus
或提升高阶单位科技。
gold through having an expansion,
所以可以选择托伦斯或奇美拉。
>> killing someone with a big army or
这些都是胜利条件。
better heroes
现在就开始吧，立即行动！
>> or going to a high unit tech.
通过此方法可建造商店。
>> So, you could go Torrance or Chimera.
建造商店可在进攻时持续补充
Those are all win conditions.
并维持单位生产。
Let's do this. Let's get it on.
现在能为山王提供清晰度再生。
>> And then with this, you can build a
我们把所有装备都到位了。
shop.
所以可以选择托伦斯或奇美拉。
Building a shop allows us to replenish
这些都是胜利条件。
and keep producing units when you're
现在就开始吧，立即行动！
attacking.
通过此方法可建造商店。
>> And now we can get like clarity regen
建造商店可在进攻时持续补充
for the mountain king.
并维持单位生产。
>> Let's get it all.
现在能为山王提供清晰度再生。
I am your servant.
我是您的仆人。
>> And then you can make towers as well.
你也能建造高塔。
>> By the power of the light.
借光明之力。
>> GG.
GG.
I'm accidentally shouting.
我不小心在吼叫。
>> GG.
GG.
Why not put some speed on me hero? Uh,
为什么不为我的英雄加加速？呃，
you can and and you should. It's good.
你可以而且应该这么做，这样做很好。
Why are you yelling? Uh, I learned using
你为什么在吼叫？呃，我之前在《帝国时代2》和《帝国时代4》中用过大写锁定键操作，
caps lock in Age of Empires 2 and 4, and
现在无意识按着它，因为
I am pressing it by accident now because
那些游戏的残留肌肉记忆，
of latent muscle memory of playing those
尽管在《魔兽争霸3》里没给这个键绑定操作，
games, even though I don't have anything
我只是随机按着Caps键，
bound to it in Warcraft 3. I'm just
结果现在控制我的声音音量很麻烦。
randomly pressing caps and having
借光明之力。
trouble controlling the volume of my
GG.
voice.
我不小心在吼叫。